Finding Aid for the John Allison Benjamin Papers Biomed.0001
UCLA Library Special Collections
- VII. NON-PRINT MATERIALS
  - VII. E. 35 mm SLIDES
    - Slide page 8 (partly from carousel), [n.d.] (Box 8, Folder 54)
      20 slides: formalized drawing of Stephens sketch, Fig. 2 of Schwarz' & Stephens' "The persistent mesonephric duct...J. Urol. 120:592"; "Vesico-ureteral reflux: Douglas Stephens and Caspar Wolff"; 3/4 -length portrait, Douglas Stephens (?); 3/4 -length portrait, Abraham Flexner; drawings, embryonic anatomy, handwritten captions in Latin; Fig. 8 from Curtis J. Lund's "Cinefluorographic studies...I."; Fig. 8 from JAB's "Cinefluorographic studies in bladder & urethral function" - also Fig. 4 from "Infection & vesicoureteral reflux"; Figs. 2 & 3 from unidentified publication: neuroreceptors, & bladder filling and emptying; unidentified portrait; unidentified portrait; title page of Theorien der Generation, by Caspar Friedrich Wolff, Berlin: F. W. Birnstiel, 1764; Figs. 1-3 of unidentified publication; Plate 5 of unidentified publication; Figs 5-7 of unidentified publication, drawings of kidney cross section (?); Dr. & Mrs. Benjamin, Drs. Mellinkoff, O'Malley & Field examining books in rare books cage; Dr. & Mrs. Allen & Chancellor Murphy in same location; Fig. 1 from unidentified publication: MRI's of brainstem glioma; Fig. 62 from unidentified publication: radiograms of pelvic stone; quote from Leonard Woolf; quote from Winston Churchill
    - Slide page 9 (from box labeled "History G.U. Ciné, up to Dec. 1975") (Box 8, Folder 55)
      20 slides: title: "The history and development of urological x-ray cinematography: the influence of Dr. John Macintyre of Glasgow"; portrait of Macintyre; holograph title: "Ueber eine neue Art von Strahlen, von W. C. Röntgen"; holograph first page of Röntgen article; typed title page of Röntgen 1895 Würzburg edition; first page of published article; Punch cartoons, 1896, re. x-rays; unidentified male portrait; 3/4 portrait, George H.S. Ramsey; portrait, James S. Watson, Jr.; portrait, Sydney A. Weinberg; 3/4 portrait, Frank Campeti; portrait, Frank Hinman, Jr.; title page of Frank Hinman, Jr.'s "Vesical physiology demonstrated by cinéradiography..."; Fig. 11 of JAB's "Urological x-ray cinematography": serial films of bladder during initiation of urination; title page from JAB's "Cinefluorographic studies of bladder and urethral function"; Fig. 1 from JAB's "Cineradiographic observations of ureteral functions in man and dog"; "X-ray movie data" on a named patient; Fig. 24 and Fig. 21 from JAB's "Urological x-ray cinematography" [RESTRICTED]
    - Slide page 10 (from box labeled "History G.U. Ciné, up to Dec. 1975") (Box 8, Folder 56)
      20 slides: Fig. 20 and Fig. 22 from JAB's "Urological x-ray cinematography"; other x-ray cinecystogram frames similar to Fig. 22; Fig. 23 & Fig. 12 from same publication; schematic drawing of sodium transport in the kidney; page of text about Waldeyer's sheath; G.U. system x-rays; quote from Ecclesiastes 1,10; quote, Friends of the UCLA Library; Dr. & Mrs. Benjamin and son in front of Benjamin Collection exhibit, 1965; Fig. 2 from JAB's "Infection and vesicoureteral reflux..."; portrait of John Scott; holographic note from Dr. Scott accompanying Macintyre cinéfilm; title page of Archives of Clinical Skiagraphy, ed. by Sidney Rowland. London: Rebman Pub. Co., 1896; p. 8 of same publication; p. 37 of that publication's successor, Archives of Skiagraphy; plate XXIV from same publication, part of which is also Fig. 3 of JAB's "Urological x-ray..."; two unidentified gentlemen on woodsy path; one frame of cinecystogram (?)
    - Slide page 11 (from box labeled "History G.U. Ciné, up to Dec. 1975") (Box 8, Folder 57)
      20 slides: frames from cinefilm; Fig. 7 from JAB's "Infection and vesicoureteral reflux"; two slides: Fig. 1 from same publication, and part of Fig. 1 with schematic drawing; x-rays of G.U. system, parts B & C, unidentified; ditto, different parts C & D; x-ray of bladder; photomicrograph, Fig. 9 of unidentified publication: photomicrograph; 2 slides: Table 1 from unidentified publication: contour changes of bladder, with & without dimensions; Fig. 1 from unidentified publication: Evolution of concept of urethral sheath; anatomical drawing of urethra; Fig. 1 from unidentified publication: Mesodermal component, female urethra; 3/4 portrait, Lord Kelvin; portrait, Sir James Graham, Duke of Montrose; Figs. 5A & B from Tessler's "Edge enhancement of renal x-ray studies"; Figs. 1A & B from same publication; Fig. 13, fig. 14 & Fig. 15 from JAB's "Urological x-ray..."
    - Slide page 12 (from unlabeled box), [n.d.] (Box 8, Folder 58)
      20 slides: "Time, accomplishments, contemplation"; quote from Matthew 5:16; five slides, courtesy of Eaton Laboratories, drawings of renal physiology; four slides, drawings of Bozzini's Lichtleiter & its principles; "Concerning the family book of learning"; title page of Journal der practischen Heilkunde, vol. 24, part 1, Berlin, 1806; title of "Catherterization of the male ureter," by James Brown, Bulletin of the Johns Hopkins Hospital, Sept. 1893; quote about the kidney; two slides, quotes from John Milton's Areopagitica, 1644; schema of kidney lymph & blood flow; drawings of species comparisons of kidney shapes; Fig. 1 of unidentified publication: reflection and refraction at air glass interface
    - Slide page 13 (from unlabeled box, etc.), [n.d.] (Box 8, Folder 59)
      20 slides: light transmission through optical fiber; table IX from unidentified publication; unidentified; kidney radiograms; two slides, G.U. x-rays; catheter insertion in ureter; digital insertion in (?); portrait of Dr. Nitze; PHS x-ray exposure study, estimated mean gonad doses, 1972; Fig. 1 from Science, 125:119, 1957; Fig. 2 of unidentified publication: three slides, pelvic x-rays; x-ray of bladder filled with contrast medium; schemtic drawing of G.U. system; quotation from Walter Hamilton Moberly; two slides of infant named patient [RESTRICTED]
    - Slide page 14 (from box labeled, "Urethral divert., Western Sect., AUA), 1973 (Box 8, Folder 60)
      20 slides: title slide for talk, Figs. 1A,B,C, Figs. 2A,B,C,D,E, Fig. 3, Figs. 4A,B,C,D,E, Figs. 5A,B,C,D,E, & Fig. 6A from JAB's "Urethral diverticulum in adult female..."
    - Slide page 15 (cont'd. from previous box, & related envelope) 1973, [n.d.] (Box 8, Folder 61)
      19 slides: Fig. 6B,C,D and Figs. 7B,C, from "Urethral diverticulum" publication, and a summary slide for talk; also, 13 additional slides from envelope labeled "Western Sect., AUA, June 24, 1973, Honolulu"
    - Slide page 16 (from box labeled, "Pediatric urology"), 1954-1955 (Box 8, Folder 62)
      19 slides: of 5 named patients, ranging from two to nine slides per patient; some pictures of the children, of surgical procedures and of the surgical field [RESTRICTED]
    - Slide page 17 (cont'd. from previous box, & from box labeled, "Dog #26, 21 Oct. 55), 1955 (Box 8, Folder 63)
      20 slides: eight slides of an additional named patient, presented at the Pediatric Section, A.U.A., May 15th, ?; twelve slides of surgical procedures and of the operative field in a dog
    - Slide page 18 (from box labeled, "Uroscopy; men judge the urine), [n.d.] (Box 8, Folder 64)
      20 slides: title & summary slides for a talk; urine wheels and other schema to classify urine, early illustrations of urinalysis, some early texts
    - Slide page 19 (cont'd. from above & another box), [n.d.] (Box 8, Folder 65)
      19 slides: four more slides on uroscopy; ancient text "Libre de receptes, 1466?"; from box labeled "History, fasciae": portrait of Petrus Camper; Fig. from unidentified publication; portrait of Dr. Gerota; drawing, abdominal cross section of infant with congenital left kidney absence; Figs. 1, 2, 4 & 5 from C.E. Tobin's "Anatomical study...fasciae limiting urinary extravasation..."; Figs. 1, 10, 11, 14 & 20 from C.E.Tobin's "Anatomical...restudy of Denonvilliers' fascia"; photograph of p. 23 from Denonvilliers' Thesis, 1837; Fig. 2 from C.E. Tobin's "Continuity of the fasciae..."
    - Slide page 20 (from miscellaneous sources), [n.d.] (Box 8, Folder 66)
      20 slides: title slide: "Probing for achievable understanding of urinary tract structures and function"; two figures from Cobb, et al., J. Urol., 1983; two histology slides of mesonephric ducts; three slides of pelvic x-rays with schematic drawings; Fig. 1, unidentified: x-rays with contrast medium of pelvic areas; Fig. 1, unidentified: dissection of trigone; Figs. 5 & 6 from JAB's "Infection and vesicoureteral reflux"; two histology slides; x-ray of G.U. system; two contrast medium slides of pelvic area; fig. From Urology 21, 239, 1983; Fig. 1 from J. Urol. 21, Whitaker; Fig. 11 from J. Urol., 1919, H.H. Young et al.; Fig. 2 from unidentified publication
    - Slide page 21 (from miscellaneous sources), [n.d.] (Box 8, Folder 67)
      20 slides: fig. from Tanagbo, Hutch, et al., 1965; Fig. 3 from J. Urol., Alfert; figure from Biology, 22(1):1983; Fig. 1 from unidentified publication: prostatic urethra; Fig. 3 from unidentified publication: drawing of ureter; schematic presentation of measurements of trigone & ureter; Figs. 7,8,9 of unidentified publication; biographical details of unknown person; Fig. 7 from Tobin's "Continuity of the fasciae..."; drawing similar to Fig. 8 from Tobin's "Anatomical study & clinical consideration..."; nine slides, Figs. 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 11, 12 & 19 from unidentified publication; title slide: "Lower tract obstruction in children, 1850-1980"
    - Slide page 22 (from miscellaneous sources), [n.d.] (Box 8, Folder 68)
      20 slides: hologram: "Dr. Bozzini/medicus ordinarius/Francofurti ad meenum"; 2 slides: full title page of article on Bozzini by Rathert, Lutzeyer & Goodwin, & title only; self-portrait of Bozzini; 2 slides: full title page of translation of Bozzini's "Lichtleiter" by Bush, et al., & title only; title page of Bozzini's Der Lichtleiter, 1807; 4 slides of drawings of the "Lichtleiter"; unlabeled portrait (Dr. Belt?); Dr. & Mrs. Benjamin and Russell Shank, Benzi acquisition honors, June 20, 1986; Dr. & Mrs. Benjamin and ?; medical artist Max Broedel and a bookplate he created; title page of Francisco Diaz' Tratado nuevamente impresso..., 1588; "chemical structure of Uroselectan"; William B. Hawkins & George H. Whipple, with signatures; Dr. Whipple in his office in 1971; portrait of Dr. Whipple
    - Slide page 23 (from miscellaneous sources), [n.d.] (Box 8, Folder 69)
      20 slides: three slides of Philip Bozzini's "Lichtleiter"; portrait of "Dr. Harvey"; three slides of speakers, "Mid-Atlantic meeting"; seven slides of typed text; x-ray of kidneys; two slides of schematic drawings; three slides of schematic drawings of G.U. tract development
    - Slide page 24 (from slotted slide box), [n.d.] (Box 8, Folder 70)
      20 slides (numbers & descriptions taken from box cover); in rabbit: #1. approach to prostate; #2. ditto; #3. prostate exposed; #4. ditto; #5. transplant to eye; #5a. ditto; #7. growing transplant; #8. colored stills (missing); #9. approach to prostate; #10. prostate exposed; #11. ditto; #12. ditto; 13. #prostate & para-prostate exposed; #14. incision in eye for transplant; #15. ditto; #16. transplantation; #17. prostate & para-prostate, dorsal; #18. prostate & para-prostate, ventral; #19. fixed specimen, G.U. tract; #20.ditto; in human: #21. prostatic ducts
    - Slide page 25 (from slotted slide box, cont'd.), [n.d.] (Box 8, Folder 71)
      20 slides (numbers & descriptions taken from box cover); in human: #22. ca. prostate duct (?) S.Vs.; #23. ditto; in opossum: #24. normal male (Burns); #25. male, genetic, testosterone; #26. male, genetic, estradiol; #27. normal female (Burns); #28. female, genetic, testosterone; #29. female, genetic, testosterone, diagram; #30. female, genetic, estradiol; #31. table: castration, effect prostate; #32. table: hypophysectomy, effect prostate & parabiosis; #33. testosterone, solubility; #34. effect-test., prost. s.v., testis ext.; in rhesus: #35. prostate, normal (Zuckerman); #36. prostate, estrone (Zuckerman); #37. utricle, normal (Zuckerman); #38. utricle, estrone (Zuckerman); in baboon: #39.utricle, normal (Zuckerman); #40. utricle, estrone (Zuckerman); in rhesus: #41. castrate, testosterone, restore s.v.
    - Slide page 26 (from slotted slide box, cont'd.), [n.d.] (Box 8, Folder 72)
      20 slides (numbers & descriptions taken from box cover); in rhesus: #42. castrate, estrone, no change in prostate; #43. castrate, estrone, hyperplasia utricle; #44. ejaculatory duct & prostate, normal; #45. animal prostate - no change in testosterone; in rabbit: #46. anatomic relationship, G.U. system; #47. prostatectomy steps; #48. transplant eye, steps; #49. fixed specimen, G.U. tract; #50. chemical formulas, male & female hormones; #51. prostatic tissue growing in eye, normal; #52. Brown-Pearse epithelioma; #53. ditto; #54; male, teratoma & gynecomastia, left testicle; #55. testosterone & transplant; #56. ditto; #57. prostate & testes out; #58. prostate & testes out & testosterone; in human: #59. age of descent of testes; in rabbit: #60. transplant, castrate; #61. transplant, castrate, testosterone
    - Slide page 27 (from slotted slide box, cont'd.), [n.d.] (Box 8, Folder 73)
      20 slides (numbers & descriptions taken from box cover); in rabbit: #62. prostatic implant, testosterone; #63. prostatic implant, castration, testosterone; in animal (?) & human: #64. kidney stone, solubility, p.H. 4.0; #65. ditto; #66. stones-h-before Rx; #67. ditto, 80 hrs. of Rx; #68. ditto, 10 days of Rx; #69. effect esters of testosterone; #70. effect, esters of testosterone, prostate, sem. ves.; #71. response, esters of testosterone, prostate, sem. ves.; #72. ca. prostate, Rx results, 2 yrs.; #73. ca. prostate, resection only or resection & x-ray; #74; distribution of tumors; #75. Asher - papiloma urethra; #76. Rohe - herpes zoster; #77. ditto; in rabbit: #78. Brown-Pease epi.; #79. ditto; in human (?): #80. pneumopyelogram - Sill.C.; #81. ditto
    - Slide page 28 (from slotted slide box, cont'd.), [n.d.] (Box 8, Folder 74)
      18 slides (numbers & descriptions taken from box cover); in human: #82. pneumopyelogram - Sill. C.; #83. prostate, embryology; #84. ditto; in rat: #85. parabiosis; #86. testosterone - chemistry; #87. castration, prostate; in human: #88. testosterone Rx; #89. ditto; #90. before & after penile amputation; #91. histology - testosterone Rx; #92. histology, prostate, no Rx; in rat: #93. prostate, before & after castration; #94. missing; #95. types of pyeloureteroplasty; #96. Drs. J.M.T. Finney, Dean Lewis & Harvey Cushing, seated, 1926; #97. prostate, Rx. stilbesterol; #98. ditto, high power; in rat: #99. female, prepubertal, testosterone; #100. diagram, prostate connections
    - Slide page 29 (from slotted slide box 2), [n.d.] (Box 8, Folder 75)
      20 slides (numbers & descriptions taken from box cover); in human: #1. prostate, before & after castration; #2. prostate, after castration; #3. spermatokinetic effect, PMS; in rabbit: #4. cleavage & blastocyst; in primates: #5. gastrulation; in human: #6. embryos; #7. embryonic testis; #8. embryoma of testis; #9. ditto; #10. ditto, chorionic epithelium; #11. diagrams - teratogenesis; #12. female endocrine physiology; #13. ovary physiology; #14. endometrium physiology; #15. male, endocrine imbalance; #16. male, prostate anatomy; #17. male, prostate adenoma; #18. male, B.P.H. & G.U. tract; #19. male, ca. prostate; #20. female, pathology
    - Slide page 30 (from slotted slide box 2, cont'd.), [n.d.] (Box 8, Folder 76)
      20 slides (numbers & descriptions taken from box cover); in human: #21. hermaphrodite; #22. spermatogenesis; #23. undescended testicle; #24. testicle infection; #25. prostate abscess; #26. testis, cancer; #27. prostatic calculi - Witherell; #28. no.16 cystoscope; #29. hypospadia, plastic surgery - Edmund.; #30. ditto; #31. Leydig cells, age, prostate; #32. prostate size, age; #33. prostate - B.P.H. vs. age, Leydig cells; #34. hydrocoele & hernia; #35. hermatocoele & varcocoele; #36. multiple cysts - DePetro; #37. ditto; #38. teratoma, testis; #39. seminoma, testis; #40. epispadia
    - Slide page 31 (from slotted slide box 2, cont'd.), [n.d.] (Box 8, Folder 77)
      20 slides(numbers & descriptions taken from box cover); in human: #41. epispadia; #42. sulfathiazole dermatitis, female - M. Davis; #43. ditto; #44-52. nephropexy - anatomy, surgery; #53. calculus Bl., male - Bassell; #54. hydronephrosis, female - Shields; #55. liver, polycystic disease; #56. papillomatous urethra - Pierce; #57. basket, stone - A. Stark; #58. kidney, hydronephrosis - Dr. Sharp; #59. testes & bc - C.L. Vaughn; #60. female, kidney, hydronephrosis - Vacher (?)
    - Slide page 32 (from slotted slide box 2, cont'd.), [n.d.] (Box 8, Folder 78)
      20 slides (numbers & descriptions taken from box cover); in human: #61. kidney stone - W.X. Foley; #62. renal ectopia - McCloud; #63. ditto; 64-67. hypospadias - McKenna; #68-80. Belt - perineal prostatectomy
    - Slide page 33 (from slotted slide box 2, cont'd., plus miscellanous), [n.d.] (Box 8, Folder 79)
      16 slides (numbers & descriptions taken from box cover); in human: #81-83. Belt, perennial prostatectomy, cont'd.; #84. diagram, kidney disease; #85-87. graphs, charts of diseases; #88. distribution, cancer of prostate; #89. implant before stilbesterol; #90. implant after stilbesterol; two slides: cross section of kidney, both labeled "no good"; four slides of dog kidneys, Nov. 1956; 4 x-rays 1
  - VII. F. LANTERN SLIDES
    - Box with 87 4 x 3 1/4 glass slides, various subjects, [n.d.] (Box 0, Folder 1)
    - Box with 83 4 x 3 1/4 glass slides, various subjects, [n.d.] (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Box with 36 4 x 3 1/4 glass slides, various subjects, [n.d.] (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - VII. G. MISCELLANEOUS AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS
    - Phonograph record, [n.d.] (Box 8, Folder 80)
      6" diameter, grooved on both sides, no identification
    - Videocassette, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 81)
      "The American Urological Association presents an interview with John A. Benjamin, M.D., conducted by Harry C. Miller, M.D., 20 May 1987." JAB spoke about teachers & mentors who influenced his life & career, about some of his most important research endeavors, and expressed some ideas on the future of urology; he also gave a short account of the doings of his four children. VHS, color, ca. 40 min.
  - VII. H. MISCELLANEOUS ITEMS
    - Tie tacks, [n.d.] (Box 9, Folder 1)
      Two identical tie tacks, with inscription "UCLA School of Medicine Aesculapians"